Guide to the P.W.R. Sexty Cigarette Cards of Ships and Locomotives, ca. 1930-1939
Department of Special Collections
P.W.R. Sexty Cigarette cards of ships and locomotives,
ca. 1930-1939
MISC 915
Sexty, P.W.R., collector.
1 v. (100 cards)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The cards are mounted in a W.D., and H.O. Will's Cigarettes (Imperial Tobacco Company of Great Britain) card album, probably dating from the early 1930s. The album is completely filled with commemorative cards representing ships and other floating objects, i.e. barges, dredges, buoys (5 pages), and locomotives of Britain, the British Commonwealth, and other countries (5 pages). Each card (1.5 x 2.0 inches) was presumably offered with a package of Will's cigarettes as a market promotion. Each card is in brilliant color and contains on the back pertinent facts relating to the object shown on the front. The collection of maritime objects ranges from working ships, passenger ships, warships, to miscellaneous craft. The locomotives shown represent the major locomotives in use in their respective countries at the time. There are 50 railway cards and 50 maritime cards.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Originally part of the Hopkins Transportation Library; transferred, 2000.
Provenance
The Collection, according to a signature on the inside of the front cover, once belonged to P.W.R. Sexty, The Vicarage. West Leamington, North Devizes [England, southeast of Birmingham, near Warwick].
Collection Scope and Content Summary
This collection consists of a single item, a W.D. and H.O. Will's Cigarettes (Imperial Tobacco Company of Great Britain) Card Album, probably dating from the early l930s. The Album is completely filled with commemorative cards representing ships and other floating objects, i.e., barges, dredges, buoys (5 pages), and locomotives of Britain, the British Commonwealth, and other countries (5 pages). Each card (l.5 x 2.0 inches) was presumably offered with a package of Will's cigarettes as a market promotion. Each card is in brilliant color and contains on the back pertinent facts relating to the object shown on the front. The collection of maritime objects ranges from working ships, passenger ships, warships, to miscellaneous craft. The locomotives shown represent the major locomotives in use in their respective countries at the time. The total number of maritime cards is 50, and the total number of railway cards is 50.
The cards are mounted in a W.D., and H.O. Will's Cigarettes (Imperial Tobacco Company of Great Britain) card album, probably dating from the early 1930s. The album is completely filled with commemorative cards representing ships and other floating objects, i.e. barges, dredges, buoys (5 pages), and locomotives of Britain, the British Commonwealth, and other countries (5 pages). Each card (1.5 x 2.0 inches) was presumably offered with a package of Will's cigarettes as a market promotion. Each card is in brilliant color and contains on the back pertinent facts relating to the object shown on the front. The collection of maritime objects ranges from working ships, passenger ships, warships, to miscellaneous craft. The locomotives shown represent the major locomotives in use in their respective countries at the time. There are 50 railway cards and 50 maritime cards.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Imperial Tobacco Company.; Will's Cigarettes.; Locomotives--Great Britain--Pictorial works.; Ships--Pictorial works.; Transportation--History.; Albums.; Cigarette cards.; Hopkins Transportation Library.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Ships
  - Subseries 1. Working Ships
    - Cable Laying Steamer: "Dominia" (Br.)1926
    - Whaling Ship: "C.A.Larsen" (U.S.)n.d.
    - Tank Barge: "Colonial Beacon" (U.S.) n.d.
    - Concrete Ship: "Nansenfjord" (Nor.)[1918 ?]
    - Dredgern.d.
    - Cargo Steamer: "Baoule" (Fr.)1921
    - Locomotive-carrying Ship: "Belljeanne (Br./Nor.) 1926
    - Boat Beacon: "Beta" (Br.) n.d.
    - Bucket Dredger: [No name] n.d.
    - Grab Dredger: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Great Lakes Freighter: [No name] (U.S./Can) n.d.
    - Floating Crane: "Mammoth" (Br.) n.d.
    - Floating Dock: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Floating Grain Elevator: [No name] n.d.
    - Floating Hotel: [No name] (U.S.) n.d.
    - Luggage Steamer: "Liscard" (Br.) 1921
    - Monitor Type Freighter: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Mud Hopper: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Hopper Dredger: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Ice Breaker: "Jaakarhu" (Fin.) n.d.
    - Cattle Motorship: "Portman" (Br.) n.d.
    - Rotor Ship: "Barbara" (Br.) n.d.
    - Collier: "Milazzo" (It.) 1916
    - Oil Barge (Ocean Going): "Navahoe" [U.S.?] n.d.
    - Oil Separator Barge: [No name] ( Br.) n.d.
    - Motor Trawler: "Victoria" (Br.) 1928
    - Whale Catcher: [No name}(Br.) n.d.
    - Lightship: "Spurn" (Br.) n.d.
  - Subseries 2. Warships
    - Ironclad Circular: "Admiral Popoff" (Rus.) n.d.
    - Aircraft Carrier: "HMS Hermes" (Br.) n.d.
    - Monitor: [No name] (Br.) [1914?]
    - Fuel Ship: "Kamoi" (Jap.) 1922
    - Patrol-Escort Boat: "Kil Boat" (Killarney Class) (Br.) [l9l4?]
    - Hospital Ship: "Nahha" (Br.) [1914?]
    - Battleship: "HMS Rodney" (Br.) 1925
    - Collier: "Jason" (U.S.)1912
    - Dirigible Mooring Ship: "Patoka" (U.S.) [1928?]
    - Submarine Tender: "Vulkan" (Ger,) 1908
    - Battleship: "HMS Warspite" (Br.) 1915
    - Steam Submarine: K-class (Br.) 1915
  - Subseries 3. Passenger Ships
    - Pleasure Boat: [No name] (Ger.) n.d.
    - Ferry Boat: "Fresno" (U.S.) [1930?]
    - Humber Ferry Steamer: "Brocklesby" (Br.) 1912
    - River Steamer: "Peter Stuyvesant" (U.S.) n.d.
    - Twin-Masted Steamer: [No name] n.d.
    - River Ferry Steamer: "Squires" (Br.) [1930?]
    - Stern Wheeler: [No name] (Br.) n.d.
    - Train Ferry: [No name] (Br.) [1914?]
  - Subseries 4. Miscellaneous Craft
    - Experimental Craft: [No name] (Fr.) n.d.
    - Mystery Tower Buoy: [No Name] (Br.) 1920
- Series 2. Locomotives
  - Subseries 1. England
    - Great Western: "King George V"
    - Great Western: "Launceston Castle"1923
    - LM & S Railway: High Pressure (Royal Scot Series)[1920's?]
    - LM & S Railway: 3-cylinder Compoundn.d.
    - LM & S Railway: "Garret" Class (Mineral)n.d.
    - LM & S Railway: 4.6.0 Express 1921 (pre)
    - LM & S Railway: "Mogul" (new version)n.d.
    - LM & S Railway: 4.6.0 "Royal Scot"n.d.
    - L & NE Railway: "Cock o' the North" (Atlantic Series)
    - L & NE Railway: 4.4.0 County Class
    - L & NE Railway: "Director" Classn.d.
    - L & NE Railway: "Enterprise" (Pacific class, USA built Baldwin)n.d.
    - L & NE Railway: GC Type 4.6.0 Expressn.d.
    - L & NE Railway: High Pressure Compound
    - L & NE Railway: ("Sandringham Class)n.d.
    - Metropolitan (London) Railway: 2.6.4. Goods Tank[1919-1920?]
    - Southern Railway: 4.4.0 Expressn.d.
    - Southern Railway: 4.6.4 "King Arthur "n.d.
    - Southern Railway: 4.4.0 "Lord Nelson"n.d.
  - Subseries 2. Other Commonwealth
    - Gold Coast Rys.: "Governor" Classn.d.
    - Kenya & Uganda Ry: 2.8.2 " Mikado" Freightn.d.
    - Rhodesian Rys: 4.8.2 Mountain, Mixed Trafficn.d.
    - South African Rys: "Beyer-Garratt"n.d.
    - South African Rys: "Modified Fairlie"n.d.
    - South African Rys: Pacific-Type Class (U.S, Baldwin)n.d.
    - Sudan Gov't Rys: 2.8.2 Mikado Freightn.d.
    - New South Wales Gov't Rys: 4.6.0 Freightn.d.
    - New South Wales Gov't Rys: 4.8.2 Freightn.d.
    - Queensland Govt. Rys: Pacific Type Classn.d.
    - So. Australian Gov't. Rys.: Pacific Type Expressn.d.
    - Victorian Gov't Rys: New Pacific Type
    - Canadian National Rys: 4.8.4 Express
    - Canadian National Rys: 2.10.2 Freight
    - Canadian Pacific Ry.: 4.8.4 Express
    - Great Southern Railway, Ireland: Mixed Traffic Express n.d.
    - New Zealand Gov't Rys: 4.6.2 Passenger "AB" Classn.d.
  - Subseries 3. Foreign Countries
    - Belgian National Ry: "Type 10" Express
    - Northern Railway (France): "Super Pacific" (Serves as "Golden Arrow")
    - German State Rys: 4.6.2 Pacific Express
    - Italian State Rys: 2.8.0 "Ansaldo" Typen.d.
    - Madrid. Zaragoza, & Alicante Ry (Spain): 4.8.2 Express
    - Baltimore & Ohio Ry (USA): "President" Class (Pacific Type)n.d.
    - Union Pacific Ry (USA): Mountain Type Expressn.d.
    - Virginia Ry (USA) [Virginia City, NV]: "Mallet " Classn.d.